Guide to the Charles Dewey Hilles Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Charles Dewey Hilles papers
1823-1955
MS 281
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
63.5
Correspondence, memoranda, speeches, press releases, clippings, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia documenting Hilles' activities as secretary to President Taft (1911-1913), as chairman and committeeman to the Republican National Committee (1912-1937) and as Assistant Secretary of the Treasury (1909-1911). His correspondence as Taft's secretary is of special importance as being originally part of the President's office files. His work as administrator of the Ohio Industrial School (1892-1902) and the New York Juvenile Asylum (1902-1909) is also documented in the correspondence. Family correspondence is particularly rich for the fall of 1911 when Hilles was touring the country with President Taft, and for 1912 just before his appointment as chairman of the Republican National Committee. Correspondents of note include Charles Francis Adams, William Jennings Bryan, Nicholas Murray Butler, Andrew Carnegie, Josephus Daniels, Charles G. Dawes, Theodore Dreiser, Henry W. Farnam, Irving Fisher, Arthur T. Hadley, Warren G. Harding, Charles Evans Hughes, Frank B. Kellogg, Henry Cabot Lodge, Gifford Pinchot, Theodore Roosevelt, Elihu Root, Henry L. Stimson, Cornelius Vanderbilt, Booker T. Washington and George Westinghouse.
Hilles, Charles Dewey, 1867-1949
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gifts of Charles Dewey Hilles, Jr., Frederick Whiley Hilles, Elizabeth Lee Hilles Reynolds.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Correspondence. II. Topical Files.
Scope and Contents
The Charles Dewey Hilles Papers (1885-1955) consists of correspondence, letterbooks, memoranda, speeches, press releases, clippings, and printed matter arranged in two series. There is also a section of oversize material.
The papers were accessioned and processed in three parts, with subsequent revisions. What follow are modified versions of the three notes on the scope and content of the papers drafted by the original processors to describe the three accessions. The first note relates mainly to the Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence, 1907-1915, and Letterpress Copybooks, 1911-1913. The second relates mainly to Correspondence, 1916-1955. The third relates to General Correspondence, 1885-1906, Family Correspondence and Miscellany (i.e. Topical Files).
The first accession of the Charles D. Hilles Papers consists of correspondence, letterbooks, clippings, scrapbooks, and printed matter from the period 1907 to 1915. About three-quarters of the letters relate to Hilles's service as secretary to President Taft (1911-1913) and chairman of the Republican National Committee (1912-1916). Most of the others are concerned with his work as First Assistant Secretary of the Treasury (1909-1911) and his continuing interest in the New York Juvenile Asylum, later the Children's Village, which he superintended between 1902 and 1909. His correspondence as Taft's secretary is especially important because it was originally part of the President's office files and therefore fills a gap in the Taft Papers in the Library of Congress. These letters were used extensively by Norman D. Wilensky in "The Republican Old Guard during Insurgency: 1908-1912" (Yale University, unpublished Ph.D. dissertation, 1961), a revision of which was published as Conservatives in the Progressive Era: The Taft Republicans of 1912, University of Florida Monographs, Social Sciences, no. 25 (Gainesville, Fla., 1965). See also his sketch of the Taft years in The Yale University Library Gazette(July 1961).
The second accession of the Charles D. Hilles Papers consists of correspondence, memoranda, speeches, press releases, and printed matter for the period 1916-1955. The majority of the items are concerned with the activities of the Republican Party on state and national levels, especially during the period of Hilles's service as Republican national committeeman from New York (1920-1937). The letters from the 1920s are mainly, though not exclusively, concerned with patronage matters. Those from the 1930s deal more with broad questions of party policy and organization.
The third accession of the Charles D. Hilles Papers spans the 1880s to the 1950s. The bulk of the items are in General Correspondence, 1885-1906, and Family Correspondence. Besides the letters there are several boxes of memorabilia, photographs, and clippings covering Hilles's entire career, all of which have been placed in Miscellany. This now makes up Series II. Topical Files.
General Correspondence, 1885-1906, was arranged alphabetically, with letters of important correspondents placed in separate folders. This section deals mainly with Hilles's work in the administration of the Ohio Boys' Industrial School (1892-1902) and the New York Juvenile Asylum (1902-1909). He was known for developing a system of competitive bidding for supplies and for successfully managing the "village system" of organization. Because his position in Ohio was controlled by political patronage, the letters deal also with the state's Republican politics. There is a list of principal correspondents in the Appendix. All non-family correspondence in the new accession written after 1906 has been interfiled with previous accessions.
Family Correspondence combines items from the new accession with letters removed from the general correspondence in the two previous accessions. The majority of the letters are to or from Charles Dewey Hilles, and these are arranged alphabetically by the name of his correspondent. Letters neither written nor received by him are filed by recipient, if known; otherwise, by author. The correspondence is especially rich for the fall of 1911, when Hilles was touring the country with President Taft, and the summer of 1912, just preceding his appointment as chairman of the Republican Party. Mrs. Hilles's letter to Bess Whiley McCracken offers a detailed description of her 1912 trip to Panama with her husband and the President.
Series II. Topical Files was created from this and previous accessions, and is arranged alphabetically by topic and/or record type. Position statements (perhaps meant as the basis for speeches) and notes on meetings, appointments, and phone calls are grouped together as Memoranda. Speeches and Writings form a separate category. Notes and printed matter related to various phases of his career are brought together in Reform School Work, Treasury Department, Taft's Secretary, and Republican Party Materials. Also included are business papers, photographs, memorabilia, clippings, and photocopies of Taft-Roosevelt correspondence (1908 Nov-1909 Mar). Refer to Appendix for a list of correspondents by subject. Note: In 1902 Hilles surveyed conditions in girls' industrial schools. Responses to his questions were received from Colorado, Connecticut, Delaware, the District of Columbia, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Maine and Massachusetts. These replies are filed under the name of the state.
The first two major accessions of the Charles D. Hilles Papers were the gift of Charles Dewey Hilles, Jr., Frederick Whiley Hilles, and Elisabeth Lee (Hilles) Reynolds. The third was donated by Frederick W. Hilles in July 1972.
Biographical / Historical
Charles D. Hilles: insurance executive and politician; Chairman of the Republican National Committee, 1912-1937; Secretary to President Taft, 1911-1913; Assistant Secretary of the Treasury, 1909-1911; administrator of the Ohio Industrial School, 1892-1902, and of the New York Juvenile Asylum, 1902-1909.
Hilles was an influential spokesman for the conservative wing of his party, and during the first two Roosevelt administrations he attained the stature of an elder statesman. In 1920 he supported Nicholas Murray Butler for the Presidency, but the Harding administration nevertheless acknowledged his prominent position in New York. A firm supporter of Coolidge, he headed the Eastern Headquarters in 1924. After the election he became the chief dispenser of federal patronage in New York and was prominent among advocates of a second candidacy in 1928. He joined with other conservative leaders in never fully accepting Hoover and his supporters; throughout his term they felt they had been pushed aside by young upstarts who knew little about running a political organization. Giving Hoover weak support in 1932, they anticipated the debacle, and after Roosevelt's victory the breach widened. Hilles came increasingly under attack for refusing to agree that the party needed thorough overhauling, and he retired from the National committee in 1937 with the admission that his post would be given to a younger man. From his retirement until his death in 1949, conservative leaders continued to seek his counsel.
APPENDIX: LIST OF CORRESPONDENCE
A select list of correspondence by subject, 1885-1906
Members of the Board of Trustees of the Ohio Boys' Industrial School
Beatty, William
Cromley, T. E.
Jennings, Malcom
Jones, Richard
Poe, E. W.
Pugsley, J. J.
Vance, John L.
White, John
Wydman, Byron
Other Members of the Staff of the Boys' Industrial Scool
Adams, C. B.
Barrett, D. M.
Hilles, William N.
Mann, George
Stirling, G. A.
Members of the Ohio State Board of Charities
Brinkerhoff, Rocliff
Byers, Joseph P.
Follett, M. D.
Platt, Rutherford
Members of the Ohio Legislature
Archer, F. B.
Barrett, D. M.
Bright, S. H.
Crafts, William H.
Cromley, T. E.
Doty, E. W.
Duff, John
Dunham, George
Duval, M. N.
McKinnon, A. S.
Marchant, Thomas
Maynard, John P.
Middleswart, S. C.
Moore, David H.
Myers, J. C.
Nippert, Carl L.
Scott, H. E.
Seese, C. F.
Sharp, R. H.
Shyrock, Charles
Swain, C. L.
Wydman, Byron S.
Other Members of Ohio State Government
Archer, E. H.
Blackburn, Joseph E.
Bushnell, Asa (Governor)
Caldwell, John A. (Lt. Governor)
Doty, E. W.
Emerson, Lauson E.
Ewing, George
Gilkey, E. Howard
Jones, John P.
Jones, John W.
McKinley, William (Governor)
Malloy, J. W.
Moore, Opha
Nash, George (Governor to whom CDH tenders resignation as superintendent of BIS)
Sheets, J. M.
Taylor, Allen
Thurber, Charles
Reynolds, Calvin
On Ohio Politics
Dick, Charles
Dover, Elmer
Hanna, Mark
Ohio Republican State Central and Executive Committees
Vance, John L.
Vorys, A. I.
White, John
New York Juvenile Asylum
Carnegie, Andrew
Garrabrandt, M.
Higley, Warren
Williams, Mornay
Other State Reform Schools
Fletcher, Bradley
Mann, George
Ohio Society of New York
Mosier, E. O.
Parker, Orrel A.
Ruch, L. C.
Ells, Warren
On Hilles Personal Business and Finance
Lummins and Parsons
Smith W. F.
Columbia Building, Loan and Finance Company
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Children -- Institutional care; Juvenile delinquency; Patronage, Political; Public welfare; Reformatories; Latin America; Middle West; New York (State); Ohio -- Politics and government; United States -- Politics and government -- 20th Century; Politicians; Adams, Charles Francis, 1835-1915; Aiken, Alfred Lawrence, 1870-1946; Ballinger, Richard Achilles, 1858-1922; Beveridge, Albert J. (Albert Jeremiah), 1862-1927; Bolton, Chester Castle, 1882-1939; Bricker, John W. (John William), 1893-1986; Broodbank, Joseph Guinness, Sir, 1857-1944; Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925; Buckner, Thomas Aylette, 1865-1942; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947; Cannon, Joseph Gurney, 1836-1926; Carnegie, Andrew, 1835-1919; Carnegie, Louise Whitfield; Coolidge, Calvin, 1872-1933; Cortelyou, George B. (George Bruce), 1862-1940; Curtis, Charles, 1860-1936; Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948; Daugherty, H. M. (Harry Micajah), 1860-1941; Dawes, Charles Gates, 1865-1951; Dewey, Charles, 1837-1917; Dickinson, J. M. (Jacob McGavock), 1851-1928; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945; Du Pont, T. Coleman (Thomas Coleman), 1863-1930; Fairbanks, Charles W. (Charles Warren), 1852-1918; Farnam, Henry W. (Henry Walcott), 1853-1933; Fisher, Irving, 1867-1947; Fisher, Walter L. (Walter Lowrie), 1862-1935; Frick, Henry Clay, 1849-1919; Garfield, James Rudolph, 1865-1950; Guggenheim, Solomon R. (Solomon Robert), 1861-1949; Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923; Hatfield, Henry Drury, 1875-1962; Hays, Will H. (Will Harrison), 1879-1954; Hill, James J. (James Jerome), 1838-1916; Hilles, Charles Dewey, 1867-1949; Hitchcock, Frank H. (Frank Harris), 1867-1935; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Houghton, Alan B.; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948; Jameson, J. Franklin (John Franklin), 1859-1937; Kellogg, Frank B. (Frank Billings), 1856-1937; Knollys, Edward George William Tyrwhitt, Viscount, 1895-; Knox, Frank, 1874-1944; Knox, Philander C. (Philander Chase), 1853-1921; Lamont, Thomas W. (Thomas William), 1870-1948; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924; MacVeagh, Franklin, 1837-1934; Marshall, John, 1881-; Martin, Joseph W. (Joseph William), 1884-1968; McAdoo, W. G. (William Gibbs), 1863-1941; McGinnies, Joseph A., 1861-1945; Meekins, Isaac Nelson, 1875-1946; Metcalf, Victor Howard, 1853-1936; Meyer, George von Lengerke, 1858-1918; Mills, Ogden Livingston, 1884-1937; Morrow, Dwight W. (Dwight Whitney), 1873-1931; Moses, George H. (George Higgins), 1869-1944; Nagel, Charles, 1849-1940; O'Laughlin, John Callan, 1873-1949; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1887-1944; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937; Scandrett, Richard Brown, 1891-; Sheffield, James R. (James Rockwell), 1864-1938; Sherman, J. S. (James Schoolcraft), 1855-1912; Snell, Bertrand Hollis, 1870-1958; Stimson, Henry L. (Henry Lewis), 1867-1950; Stuart, Campbell, 1885-; Sullivan, Mark, 1874-1952; Taft, Charles Phelps, 1843-1929; Taft, Helen Herron, 1861-1943; Taft, Henry W. (Henry Waters), 1859-1945; Taft, Horace Dutton, 1861-1943; Taft, Hulbert, 1877-1959; Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953; Taft, Wallbridge Smith, 1884-1951; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930; Taylor, Myron Charles, 1874-1959; Tumulty, Joseph P. (Joseph Patrick), 1879-1954; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951; Vanderbilt, Cornelius, 1873-1942; Wadsworth, James Wolcott, 1846-1926; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915; Weeks, John W. (John Wingate), 1860-1926; Westinghouse, George, 1846-1914; Wickersham, George W. (George Woodward), 1858-1936; Wilson, James, 1835-1920; Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927; Boys' Industrial School (Lancaster, Ohio); New York Juvenile Asylum (Dobbs Ferry, N.Y.); Ohio Society of New York; Republican Party (N.Y.); Republican Party (Ohio)
- Correspondence, 1885-1955; Series I; (139 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains files arranged in six sections: General correspondence, 1885-1906; Incoming correspondence, 1907-1915; Outgoing correspondence, 1907-1915; Letterpress copybooks, 1911-1913; General correspondence, 1916-1955; Family correspondence, 1885-1955.
  - General correspondence, 1885-1906
    - A - B (Box 1, Folder 1-24)
    - C - E (Box 2, Folder 25-50)
    - F - K (Box 3, Folder 51-88)
    - L - O (Box 4, Folder 89-114)
    - O - Sh (Box 5, Folder 115-136)
    - Si - V (Box 6, Folder 137-155)
    - W - Z (Box 7, Folder 156-169)
  - Incoming correspondence
    - 1907 January - 1908 March (Box 8, Folder 170-185)
    - 1908 April - 1909 March 16 (Box 9, Folder 186-204)
    - 1909 May 17 - May 12 (Box 10, Folder 205-221)
    - 1909 May 13 - July 14 (Box 11, Folder 222-238)
    - 1909 July 15 - September 8 (Box 12, Folder 239-249)
    - 1909 September 9 - October 31 (Box 13, Folder 250-260)
    - 1909 November 1 - December 9 (Box 14, Folder 261-272)
    - 1909 December 10 - 1910 January 17 (Box 15, Folder 273-283)
    - 1910 January 18 - March 4 (Box 16, Folder 284-294)
    - 1910 March 5 - April 13 (Box 17, Folder 295-305)
    - 1910 April 14 - June 3 (Box 18, Folder 306-316)
    - 1910 June 4 - July 8 (Box 19, Folder 317-326)
    - 1910 July 9 - July 31 (Box 20, Folder 327-336)
    - 1910 August 1 - August 16 (Box 21, Folder 337-345)
    - 1910 August 17 - September 1 (Box 22, Folder 346-354)
    - 1910 September 2 - September 16 (Box 23, Folder 355-365)
    - 1910 September 17 - October 17 (Box 24, Folder 366-376)
    - 1910 October 18 - November 4 (Box 25, Folder 377-387)
    - 1910 November 5 - December 6 (Box 26, Folder 388-398)
    - 1910 December 7 - December 31 (Box 27, Folder 399-409)
    - 1911 January 1 - January 29 (Box 28, Folder 410-419)
    - 1911 January 30 - February 28 (Box 29, Folder 420-429)
    - 1911 March 1 - March 24 (Box 30, Folder 430-442)
    - 1911 March 25 - May 11 (Box 31, Folder 443-459)
    - 1911 May 12 - June 7 (Box 32, Folder 460-471)
    - 1911 June 8 - June 23 (Box 33, Folder 472-482)
    - 1911 June 24 - July 6 (Box 34, Folder 483-493)
    - 1911 July 7 - July 21 (Box 35, Folder 494-505)
    - 1911 July 22 - August 2 (Box 36, Folder 506-517)
    - 1911 August 3 - August 16 (Box 37, Folder 518-528)
    - 1911 August 17 - September 6 (Box 38, Folder 529-540)
    - 1911 September 7 - October 28 (Box 39, Folder 541-553)
    - 1911 October 29 - December 4 (Box 40, Folder 554-564)
    - 1911 December 5 - December 27 (Box 41, Folder 565-576)
    - 1911 December 28 - 1912 January 9 (Box 42, Folder 577-589)
    - 1912 January 10 - January 21 (Box 43, Folder 590-601)
    - 1912 January 22 - January 27 (Box 44, Folder 602-613)
    - 1912 January 27 - February 1 (Box 45, Folder 614-624)
    - 1912 February 2 - February 6 (Box 46, Folder 625-634)
    - 1912 February 6 - February 10 (Box 47, Folder 635-646)
    - 1912 February 11 - February 15 (Box 48, Folder 647-658)
    - 1912 February 16 - February 19 (Box 49, Folder 659-669)
    - 1912 February 20 - February 23 (F-J) (Box 50, Folder 670-680)
    - 1912 February 23 (K-R) - February 26 (L-P) (Box 51, Folder 681-690)
    - 1912 February 26 (R-W) - February 28 (S-W) (Box 52, Folder 691-699)
    - 1912 February 29 - March 1 (Box 53, Folder 700-708)
    - 1912 March 2 - March 5 (A-J) (Box 54, Folder 709-718)
    - 1912 March 5 (K-Z) - March 8 (L-Z) (Box 55, Folder 719-728)
    - 1912 March 9 (B-H) - March 13 (A-K) (Box 56, Folder 729-739)
    - 1912 March 13 (L-W) - March 19 (A-F) (Box 57, Folder 740-750)
    - 1912 March 19 (G-W) - March-25 (A-E) (Box 58, Folder 751-761)
    - 1912 March 25 (F-W) - March 30 (A-G) (Box 59, Folder 762-771)
    - 1912 March 30 (H-W) - April 4 (Box 60, Folder 772-780)
    - 1912 April 5 - April 10 (Box 61, Folder 781-790)
    - 1912 April 11 - April 17 (A-L) (Box 62, Folder 791-800)
    - 1912 April 17 (M-Y) - April 23 (M-Y) (Box 63, Folder 801-811)
    - 1912 April 24 (A-J) - April 30 (Box 64, Folder 812-821)
    - 1912 May 1 - May 8 (Box 65, Folder 822-831)
    - 1912 May 9 - May 17 (Box 66, Folder 832-841)
    - 1912 May 18 - May 28 (Box 67, Folder 842-850)
    - 1912 May 29 - June 7 (Box 68, Folder 851-861)
    - 1912 June 8 - June 21 (Box 69, Folder 862-870)
    - 1912 June 22 - June 29 (A-J) (Box 70, Folder 871-882)
    - 1912 June 29 (K-W) - July 10 (A-L) (Box 71, Folder 883-894)
    - 1912 July 10 (M-W) - July 22 (Box 72, Folder 895-907)
    - 1912 July 23 - August 8 (Box 73, Folder 908-920)
    - 1912 August 9 - August 21 (Box 74, Folder 921-932)
    - 1912 August 22 - September 9 (Box 75, Folder 933-943)
    - 1912 September 11 - September 21 (Box 76, Folder 944-953)
    - 1912 September 22 - October 4 (A-G) (Box 77, Folder 954-965)
    - 1912 October 4 (H-W) - October 14 (A-J) (Box 78, Folder 966-977)
    - 1912 October 14 (K-Y) - October 25 (Box 79, Folder 978-988)
    - 1912 October 26 - November 3 (Box 80, Folder 989-1000)
    - 1912 November 4 - November 18 (Box 81, Folder 1001-1013)
    - 1912 November 19 - 1913 February 4 (Box 82, Folder 1014-1025)
    - 1913 February 5 - 1915 December 22 (Box 83, Folder 1026-1030)
  - Outgoing correspondence
    - 1907 March - 1908 July 31 (Box 84, Folder 1031-1041)
    - 1908 August - 1909 June 12 (Box 85, Folder 1042-1053)
    - 1909 June 13 - August 2 (Box 86, Folder 1054-1065)
    - 1909 August 3 - October 25 (Box 87, Folder 1066-1078)
    - 1909 October 26 - December 9 (Box 88, Folder 1079-1091)
    - 1909 December 10 - 1910 January 18 (Box 89, Folder 1092-1104)
    - 1910 January 19 - April 2 (Box 90, Folder 1105-1115)
    - 1910 April 3 - July 10 (Box 91, Folder 1116-1127)
    - 1910 July 11 - September 27 (Box 92, Folder 1128-1140)
    - 1910 September 28 - November 30 (Box 93, Folder 1141-1153)
    - 1910 December 1 - 1911 February 11 (Box 94, Folder 1154-1166)
    - 1911 February 13 - April 25 (Box 95, Folder 1167-1179)
    - 1911 May 2 - 1912 March 7 (Box 96, Folder 1180-1200)
    - 1912 March 8 - July 29 (Box 97, Folder 1201-1224)
    - 1912 August - October 9 (Box 98, Folder 1225-1246)
    - 1912 October 10 - 1915 November (Box 99, Folder 1247-1265)
  - Letterpress copybooks
    - Political
      - 1911 May 24 - 1912 January 5 (Box 100, Folder 1266-1268)
      - 1912 January 6 - February 23 (Box 101, Folder 1269-1271)
      - 1912 February 23 - March 14 (Box 102, Folder 1272-1274)
      - 1912 November 12 - April 3 (Box 103, Folder 1275-1277)
      - 1912 April 3 - April 24 (Box 104, Folder 1278-1280)
      - 1912 April 24 - May 31 (Box 105, Folder 1281-1283)
      - 1912 May 24 - June 24 (Box 106, Folder 1284-1285)
      - 1912 June 24 - July 11 (Box 107, Folder 1286-1288)
      - 1912 July 11 - August 24 (Box 108, Folder 1289-1291)
      - 1912 August 26 - 1913 February 27 (Box 109, Folder 1292-1293)
    - Personal
      - 1911 April 5 - December 9 (Box 110, Folder 1294-1295)
      - 1911 December 11 - 1913 March 1 (Box 111, Folder 1296-1297)
  - General correspondence, 1916-1955
    - 1916 January - 1919 June (Box 112, Folder 1298-1316)
    - 1919 July - 1921 March (Box 113, Folder 1317-1334)
    - 1921 April - 1922 December (Box 114, Folder 1335-1356)
    - 1923 January - October (Box 115, Folder 1357-1369)
    - 1923 November - 1924 December (Box 116, Folder 1370-1389)
    - 1925 January - 1928 August (Box 117, Folder 1390-1418)
    - 1928 September - 1930 December (Box 118, Folder 1419-1439)
    - 1931 January - 1933 January (Box 119, Folder 1440-1462)
    - 1933 February - 1934 January 20 (Box 120, Folder 1463-1491)
    - 1934 January 21 - July (Box 121, Folder 1492-1517)
    - 1934 August - 1935 April 7 (Box 122, Folder 1518-1541)
    - 1935 April 8 - October 8 (Box 123, Folder 1542-1566)
    - 1935 October 9 - 1936 March 21 (Box 124, Folder 1567-1595)
    - 1936 March 22 - September 14 (Box 125, Folder 1596-1619)
    - 1936 September 15 - 1937 April 30 (Box 126, Folder 1620-1646)
    - 1937 May 1 - September 30 (Box 127, Folder 1647-1670)
    - 1937 October 1 - 1938 July 31 (Box 128, Folder 1671-1697)
    - 1938 August l - 1939 October 31 (Box 129, Folder 1698-1723)
    - 1939 November 1 - 1941 (Box 130, Folder 1724-1758)
    - 1942 January 1 - 1944 July 31 (Box 131, Folder 1759-1793)
    - 1944 August 1 - 1947 June 30 (Box 132, Folder 1794-1821)
    - 1947 July 1 - 1949 April 30 (Box 133, Folder 1822-1859)
    - 1949 May 1 - 1955 (Box 134, Folder 1860-1873)
    - Incomplete material (Box 134, Folder 1874-1875)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 134, Folder 1876)
    - Undated Correspondence (Box 134, Folder 1877-1878)
    - Handwritten drafts (Box 134, Folder 1879)
  - Family correspondence
    - Anderson, Maria Lee Hilles, 1891-1895 (Box 135, Folder 1880)
    - Anderson, Thomas A., 1896 (Box 135, Folder 1881)
    - Coale, Margaret, 1907-1909 (Box 135, Folder 1882)
    - Hilles, Anna, 1900-1911 (Box 135, Folder 1883-1884)
    - Hilles, Charles Dewey Jr., 1905-1918 (Box 135, Folder 1885)
    - Hilles, Elizabeth Lee, 1890-1912 (Box 135, Folder 1886)
    - Hilles, F. Waldo and Lela, 1900-1909 (Box 135, Folder 1887)
    - Hilles, Frederick Whiley, 1905 (Box 135, Folder 1888-1890)
    - Hilles, George E. - Raymond W., 1901-1913 (Box 135, Folder 1891)
    - Hilles, Samuel, 1894-1900 (Box 135, Folder 1892)
    - Hilles, Samuel E., 1897-1911 (Box 135, Folder 1893)